We're supposed to be at a rock concert,
我们本该去看摇滚演唱会的
but all I see is-- rock.
可我却在这儿…看石头
Relax, Miko.
别急 神子
The show doesn't start for two hours.
演出还有两个小时才开始呢
Do you know how long I've waited to see Slash Monkey?
知道我为“歪猴子”乐队等了多久吗？
Eh...
呃…
Forever!
一辈子了！
And it's their only U.S. date!
而且他们只来美国一次！
There's a shock.
居然只来一次
I mean, who doesn't love obscure Bulgarian shriek metal?
那个三流保加利亚嚎叫乐队 太不给面子了
By all appearances the mines' been stripped.
从各方面来看 这个矿已经被采空了
But I'm getting a signal.
可我发现了一个信号
It's faint, but it's definitely energon.
虽然很微弱 但绝对是能量
Whoa...
哇…
Doesn't make sense.
这不合常理
This operation's been abadoned four, maybe five years?
挖掘行动四五年前就终止了吧？
And Decepticons never leave energon behind.
霸天虎从不落下一丁点儿能量
Eh, guys?
呃 各位？
Cool!
酷！
She went in.
她怎么进去了
Unbelievable.
难以置信
Really? Have you... met her?
真的？你还不了解她吗？
Eh, Miko. Get back here!
呃 神子 快回来！
It would be kind of interesting to see.
里面的东西应该挺有趣
You know, if it were...
其实应该…
Safe?
很安全？
A stripped mine can be structurally unstable, Jack.
枯矿的架构很不稳定 杰克
I promise to step lightly.
我保证轻拿轻放
Just... don't tell your mom.
那就…别告诉你妈
Ah, Lord Megatron.
啊 威震天陛下
Far be it from me to question your intentions,
我决不是在以下犯上
but I do not understand why we return here after all this time, alone?
但我不明白 我们干嘛要偷偷摸摸地回到这个…老地方？
Every last trace of energon was extracted from this mine.
我们榨干了矿里的最后一丝能量
There is nothing left.
什么都没留下
Indulge me, Starscream, won't you?
不要多嘴行吗 红蜘蛛？
Miko!
神子
- Mi...
- 神…
- Check it out!
- 看看这里！
Now, this would make an awesome rehearsal space.
在这儿排练再好不过了
Hello! Hello Cleveland.
你好！你好 克利夫兰
Are you ready to rock?
准备好摇滚了吗？
Whoooooohaaaaa... whoa!
喔――哈――哇！
Arcee, found something.
阿尔茜 有发现
Bulkhead? Bulkhead, do you read?
隔板？隔板 你听见了吗？
Scrap.
见鬼
The mineral composition down here is causing interference.
地下矿藏对信号有干扰
OK, maybe the acoustics aren't perfect.
好吧 音效可能还不够完美
Over here.
就是这儿
Ratch's gonna want a sample.
应该给老救带个样本
How intriguing.
很有趣嘛
Ehhhh, incompetent fools!
呃…一群笨蛋！
This mining equipment should have been relocated.
这套挖掘设备早该被调走了
Why is it still here?
怎么还在这儿？
A most valid question.
问得好
My apologies, master.
我很抱歉 主人
I believe Soundwave was in charge of coordinating transport.
我记得负责调度的是声波
But in fairness,
不过说句实话
during your inter-stellar travels, we all had to assume additional responsibilities.
在您做星际旅行期间 我们都身兼数职
Clearly, mistakes were made.
难免有些失误
Yes, clearly.
是的 难免
Every last trace of energon extracted?
这也叫榨干了？
Lord Megatron, I can explain.
威震天陛下 我可以解释
Explain what?
解释什么？
That you've been hoarding a supply of energon for your personal use?
解释你为什么私藏能量储备？
No! Not exactly. You said...
不！不能这么说 您说过…
Do not take me for a fool, Starscream!
你当我是傻子吗 红蜘蛛？
I have been wise to your transgressions from the beginning.
我从一开始就知道你在打小算盘
Not only did you pluck the Dark Energon from my chest
你不但取走我胸口的黑暗能量
in a failed attempt to snuff my spark,
试图杀我而未遂
but you tried to raise your own undead warrior with it.
还用它召唤了你自己的不死战士
It's no secret that you lost an arm in the process,
你为此断臂的事情已经不再是秘密
which you've since had replaced.
尽管你修复得完好如初
You know about that?!
这您都知道？！
Soundwave is quite competent in surveillance.
声波很擅长监视
I can assure you.
你大可放心
The fact is, Starscream,
事实上 红蜘蛛
despite your treachery,
尽管你在暗中捣鬼
I've allowed you to carry on this long
但我总是睁一只眼 闭一只眼
But you finally become tiresome, predictable.
可惜你越来越惹人讨厌 明知故犯
You hit rock bottom.
你休想翻身了
Master, please! Give me one more chance!
主人 求求您！再给我一次机会！
I beg of you!
我给您磕头！
You have ceased to be of use to me, Starscream,
你对我已经毫无用处了 红蜘蛛
so you shall simply cease to be.
所以 你就放心地去吧
Stay down!
蹲下！
Starscream! You dare abandon me?
红蜘蛛！你敢抛下我？
Scrap!
见鬼！
What? No!
什么？不！
Arcee?
阿尔茜？
Arcee!
阿尔茜！
Oh, scrap.
噢 见鬼
Did I do that?
是我干的吗？
Don't think so.
我看不像
You OK?
你还好吗？
Natch. What about you?
好着呢 你呢？
Peachy...
好得不得了…
Whoa...
喔…
Don't worry, Miko.
别担心 神子
I got it under control.
我能顶住
What do you think caused the cavein?
你知道为什么塌方吗？
Who knows.
天晓得
I just hope Arcee and Jack are safe, 'cause...
但愿阿尔茜和杰克都平安 因为…
We can definitely use an assist.
我们肯定需要帮手
Just keep raising that roof, Bulk.
你负责顶天立地 小隔
I'll get us outta here.
我来想办法出去
Hahahaha... Predictable, master?
哈哈…明知故犯 主人？
Is that what you called me?
你就这么评价我吗？
Well, now, who has hit rock bottom?
现在轮到谁翻不了身？
What's that? I'm sorry.
说什么？对不起
I can't hear you beneath all that rubble.
隔着一座五行山 我什么都听不清
Hahahaha... Farewell, Lord Megatron.
哈哈…告辞了 威震天陛下！
May you rust in peace!
愿你一锈到底！
But you have survived far worse.
不过 这种遭遇对你来说是小儿科
If you managed to free yourself,
如果你自己逃了出来
you would blame me for your setback.
就会怪罪我见死不救
And there is no word that I could possibly escape from your wrath.
你发火的时候 我肯定会理亏
Or worse yet,
更不用说
your mindless followers will come looking for you,
那些傻瓜随从肯定会来找你
and take credit for your rescue.
并因为营救你而立功
Credit, that could rightfully be mine.
这个功劳 应该属于我
Ah! Megatron!
啊！威震天！
Arcee?
阿尔茜？
Bulkhead?
隔板？
Miko?
神子？
Oh, that could come in handy.
噢 那东西应该有用
Miko.
神子
I'm feeling strong.
我力大无穷
No, you're not.
不 你不行了
I just need to... rest for a second.
我只需要…休息一会儿…
That's all.
就够了
Miko, listen to me.
神子 听我说
There is no fresh air down here.
这下面没有新鲜空气
If you use up the oxygen too fast...
如果你消耗氧气太快…
We could suffocate!
我们会窒息！
Not we, Miko, you!
不是我们 神子 是你！
Autobots don't need to breathe, remember?
汽车人不需要呼吸 你忘了？
Right! Smack down in outter space.
对啊！是从外太空降临的
That was cool...
太厉害了…
OK, what if I just... slow down,
好吧 要不我就…慢一点
breathe... less.
减少…呼吸
No. You need to stop, now.
不 你必须立即住手
I can't, Bulk.
不行 小隔
I have to get you out of here.
我必须救你出去
Miko, please, don't worry about me.
神子 拜托 别担心我
I'm fine.
我很好
Roll out.
出发
Do you hear that?
你听到了吗？
Sounds like...
听起来像…
Drilling.
钻探机
Got to be Arcee and Jack.
一定是阿尔茜和杰克
We are in... here!
我们在…这儿！
Here...
这儿…
Miko, grab something, and bang it on my foot.
神子 找个东西 砸我的脚
Can you do that?
你能行吗？
I don't want to hurt you.
我不想伤着你
I know it's hard to believe,
我不是吹牛
but I'm tougher than I look.
我可是超级结实
Give it all you got.
用尽全力砸
I suppose,
我猜…
helping those less fortunate would be completely out of the question.
帮助倒霉鬼脱困 是你最不想做的事
If that is the case,
如果真的是那样
you might as well use your drill to finish me.
你可以用钻头把我杀掉
I guarantee you will never have a better opportunity than right now.
我保证 你以后再也不会有这么好的机会了
Well, what are you waiting for?
好了 你还等什么？
Think of the glory--seize the day!
这是莫大的荣耀 机不可失！
Optimus would.
擎天柱会趁机动手的
No, he wouldn't.
不 他不会
Not like this.
这是乘人之危
I will be sure to share the details of our little conversation with Optimus--
我一定会把今天的对话内容 一五一十告诉擎天柱――
the day I rip out his spark!
然后扯出他的火种！
That a girl.
好姑娘
What was that?
刚才什么声音？
Nothing.
没什么
Go on, keep banging.
来吧 继续砸
Bulkhead, what's happening? Tell me!
隔板 怎么回事？告诉我！
My arms... they're starting to give...
我的手臂…快撑不住了…
Does it hurt?
疼吗？
A little.
有点
Bulkhead!
隔板！
Help's coming.
帮手来了
We just got to guide them here.
我们得把他们引过来
Hit me again!
再砸一次！
Miko, do it!
神子 动手！
Are they any closer?
他们靠近了吗？
I can't tell.
我听不出来
The sound is all...
这里的回声…
freaky in here!
太难听了！
Hahaha, yes!
哈哈…太好了！
Arcee found us!
阿尔茜找到我们了！
Hahahaha... Put any doubt of my allegiance to rest.
哈哈哈…不要再质疑我的忠诚了…
What's he doing down here?
他来干嘛？
Miko, get behind me, now!
神子 躲到我身后 快！
Well, well, if it isn't Bulkhead and his pet vermin.
哎呀呀 这不是隔板和他的宠物小臭虫嘛
My, you do have your hands full, don't you, Autobot?
哎哟 看来你腾不出手了 是吧 汽车人？
Do whatever you want to me, Starscream.
要打就冲我来 红蜘蛛
But let the human go!
先放人类走！
No. I'm not leaving you.
不 我不离开你
It appears that the human wishes to remain.
看来 这个人类想留下
Starscream, don't push me.
红蜘蛛 别逼我
You like playing with the big robots, don't you, little girl?
你喜欢跟大机器人一起玩 对不对 小姑娘？
That's it, Autobot!
够了 汽车人！
I will...
我要…
What? You'll what?
什么？你要干什么？
Maybe bring down the ceiling on top of all of us?
让这块巨石砸到我们俩头上吗？
Run, Miko!
快跑 神子！
Yes, run, Miko.
没错 跑吧 神子
I would love to see you try.
我想看看你如何逃命
Really, I would.
说真的 我想看看
Ah!
啊！
Jack, get Miko out of here, now!
杰克 带神子离开这儿 快！
Come on, come on!
上来 上来！
Run, Miko!
快跑 神子！
We can't leave Bulkhead!
我们不能丢下隔板！
And then there were two.
杀两个 赚一双
Arcee will save him, won't she?
阿尔茜会来救他的 对吗？
You and I just need to find a way out of here before Megatron digs himself free.
趁威震天爬出来之前 我们俩得想办法逃出去
Megatron's here, too?
威震天也来了？
If you think I'm gonna beg for mercy, Starscream,
以为我会求饶吗 红蜘蛛
forget it!
省省吧！
Well, you're much more valuable to me alive.
不过 把你活捉 我就立大功了
Imagine Megatron's appreciation when I not only rescue him,
威震天该对我刮目相看 我不光救了他
but deliver a Autobot.
还抓了个汽车人
I believe that would restore my statue quite nicely.
那样一来 我就可以重振雄风了
Don't move, Starscream.
别动 红蜘蛛
Hey, Bulk.
嘿 小隔
Hey, Cee.
嘿 小茜
Raise your hands.
举起手来
Oh...
噢…
We could finish him, here and now.
我们可以就地解决他
Shame I didn't bring any grenades.
可惜我没带手雷
Would Optimus finish them?
如果换成擎天柱 会下手吗？
No, he probably wouldn't.
不 他多半不会
Not like this.
这是乘人之危
But Optimus wouldn't rescue them, either. Right?
但擎天柱也不会救他们的 对吧？
Let's go home.
我们回家吧
Master. You are alive!
主人 您还活着！
Thank the Allspark!
感谢火种源！
I did not abandon you, master.
我没有抛下您 主人
I returned... to save you!
我回来…是要救您！
Save me?
救我？
Look into my spark, Lord Megatron.
火种可鉴 威震天陛下
My intentions were true.
我是真心的！
Please, have mercy!
求求您 发发慈悲吧！